<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2019 Rob Loach <robloach@gmail.com> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.libretro.RetroArch</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.libretro.RetroArch.desktop</launchable>
  <name>RetroArch</name>
  <summary>Frontend for emulators, game engines and media players</summary>
  <developer_name>libretro</developer_name>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.retroarch.com</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.libretro.com</url>
  <url type="faq">https://retroarch.com/?page=faq</url>
  <url type="donation">https://retroarch.com/index.php?page=donate</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>RetroArch main menu</caption>
      <image type="source" width="1600" height="900">https://rawgit.com/flathub/org.libretro.RetroArch/master/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>RetroArch running the NES</caption>
      <image type="source" width="1135" height="638">https://rawgit.com/flathub/org.libretro.RetroArch/master/screenshot-2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>RetroArch running Sheep It Up on the Gameboy</caption>
      <image type="source" width="1332" height="749">https://rawgit.com/flathub/org.libretro.RetroArch/master/screenshot-3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>RetroArch running the Super Nintendo</caption>
      <image type="source" width="1172" height="659">https://rawgit.com/flathub/org.libretro.RetroArch/master/screenshot-4.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <description>
    <p>
      RetroArch enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all.
    </p>
    <p>
      It enables you to run classic games on a wide range of computers and consoles through its slick graphical interface. Settings are also unified so configuration is done once and for all. RetroArch has advanced features like shaders, netplay, rewinding, next-frame response times, runahead, and more!
    </p>
  </description>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.8.2" date="2019-12-28">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-8-2-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>BUG/CRASH/GLSLANG: Fix glslang crashing error - managed to reproduce an issue which has been plaguing
          users for a while, where glslang throws an assert after closing a game (and starting a new one). This would affect all video drivers that use Slang for shaders, such as D3D10/11/12/Vulkan/Metal.</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Display Unofficial and Unsupported achievement states.</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Pass RetroArch and core versions through User-Agent HTTP header.</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Use PSX.EXE if SYSTEM.CNF cannot be found</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Prevent loading state while achievements are still being fetched from server.</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Pause hardcore if core doesn't support achievements.</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS/CRASH: Fix AddressSanitizer + CHD cause hard crash when Cheevos are enabled.</li>
          <li>CORE UPDATER: Only download when new core is available.</li>
          <li>CORE UPDATER: Add option to update all installed cores.</li>
          <li>DRM/KMS: Better detection for the current video mode.</li>
          <li>DYNAMIC RATE CONTROL: Support DRC even when using a vsync swap interval higher than 1.</li>
          <li>FFMPEG CORE: Hardware accelerated video decoding.</li>
          <li>FFMPEG CORE: Implement send/receive encoding API, will allow for hardware accelerated AMD video encoding.</li>
          <li>FFMPEG CORE: The video FIFO can be removed, since we have a ring buffer in its place. This removes unneeded copy operations and as a positive side improves overall decoding speed. Makes 8k60p SW and 4k60p HW decoding feasible on many systems. For now the ring buffer is 32 images deep. This limitation will be removed, once audio and video decoder have their own packet handling.</li>
          <li>INPUT: Fix 'Analog stick controls menu even if autoconfig disabled'.</li>
          <li>INPUT/TURBO: Added alternate Turbo-Mode 'Single Button' - For systems supporting only a single button, the turbo-button will toggle firing that button without the need to hold it. When holding the button turbo will be suspended and resumed when the button is released. Holding the button may have a different function to just tapping it.</li>
          <li>INPUT/ANALOG: Fix radial analog deadzone scaling.</li>
          <li>INPUT/ANALOG: Implement proper analog button deadzone.</li>
          <li>INPUT/MENU: Analog stick controls menu even if autoconfig disabled.</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation.</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update French translation.</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation.</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese Brazilian Translation.</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Turkish translation.</li>
          <li>LINUX/LOCALIZATION: Correct Droid Sans Fallback font path in Linux. This should fix Chinese/Korean font display issues on Fedora/RHEL/CentOS/openSUSE/SLE.</li>
          <li>MENU/BUGFIX: When using a keyboard/gamepad/mouse wheel to navigate, the menu scroll position is always maintained and updated in a consistent (and expected) fashion.</li>
          <li>MENU/BUGFIX: When resizing the window, or changing the orientation of a mobile device, the current scroll position is correctly preserved.</li>
          <li>MENU/BUGFIX: All 'normal' pointer input is now inhibited when showing message boxes.</li>
          <li>MENU/BUGFIX: The pointer actions 'select' and 'cancel' both now properly close a message box if it is currently being shown.</li>
          <li>MENU/BUGFIX: Pointer 'select' and 'cancel' actions are now inhibited when an input bind dialog is active.</li>
          <li>MENU/INPUT: Change 'User' terminology to 'Port' for input binding.</li>
          <li>MENU/LINUX: Add proper drives to Load Content.</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Halt scrolling when pointer is pressed/stationary.</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Dual thumbnail view.</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Fullscreen thumbnail viewer for boxart.</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Scroll rapidly by press and holding the scrollbar.</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: New theme 'Flux'.</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Thumbnails now have a fade-in animation.</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Fullscreen thumbnail viewer for boxart and pictures.</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Fix dock titles getting cut off</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Fullscreen thumbnail viewer for boxart and pictures</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide 'Disallow Non-Slave Mode Clients' if 'Allow Slave-Mode Clients' is disabled.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Hide 'Show desktop menu on startup' if 'Desktop menu' setting itself is disabled.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Reimplement Quick Menu - > Shaders -> Watch shader files for changes - can now be turned on/off through touch.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Refactor Quick Menu - Controls - each port now has its own submenu.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Quick Menu - Cheats - Delete All no longer requires five right button presses - this should fix this functionality for mobile touch users too.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Hide Refresh Rate options when Threaded Video is enabled - these settings do nothing with Threaded Video.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Hide Logging Verbosity levels behind Logging Verbosity.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Get rid of 'Port Number' label for Port Binds screen.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY/MOBILE: Should no longer crash when clicking on a cheat entry.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Shader parameters now have a dropdown list.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Shader passes now has a dropdown list.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Video - Hide Windowed Mode settings selectively.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Video - Hide Fullscreen Mode settings if windowed mode is not supported by context driver.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide Network Command Port.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide Relay Server Location.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: User Interface -> Appearance - Selectively hide XMB Horizontal Animation setting.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Playlists - more selective hiding.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide Rewind Settings.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide Overlay Settings.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide FPS Update Interval based on Display Framerate being enabled.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selectively hide Onscreen Notifications BG Color Settings.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Settings -> Logging - Hide 'Log To File Timestamp' if 'Log To File' is disabled.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Video -> Scaling - Hide Custom Viewport X/Y when Integer Scale is enabled as description indicates.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Achievement submenu - selectively hide.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Settings -> Video -> Aspect ratio - selectively hide/show values based on whether you have Custom or Config selected.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Settings -> Video -> Selectively hide Hard Sync.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Settings -> Video -> Implement selective hiding for VSync and Hard Sync.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Selective hiding of Runahead settings based on global setting.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Add Input -> Haptic Feedback submenu.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Add Input -> Menu Controls submenu.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Settings -> Video -> Max Swapchain Images - Add OK action.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Input - Implement OK action for Bind Hold, Turbo Period and Duty Cycle.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Input - Hotkey Binds refactor.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Move 'Press Quit Twice' and 'Menu Toggle Gamepad Combo' to Input -> Hotkey Binds.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Video - Add sublabel for Video Output submenu.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY:  If 'Favorites Tab' is disabled, don't show 'Add To Favorites' option in Quick Menu/Playlist menu.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: If On-Demand Thumbnail Downloader is enabled, hide 'Download Thumbnails' from playlist menu screen.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Add Audio Driver setting to Audio -> Output.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Add Audio -> Resampler settings.</li>
          <li>MENU/USABILITY: Add Audio -> Output and Audio -> Synchronization.</li>
          <li>OPENGL: Shaders are now working properly (only in OpenGL) when rotating both from Core API rotation and from menu video rotation. The fix is clearly visible with crt-royale for example.</li>
          <li>OPENGL: 1:1 PAR is now correct when rotating (both from Core API rotation and from menu video rotation, as you said, in the latter case you currently have to change Aspect Ratio after menu video rotation for it to work).</li>
          <li>OPENGL: When using Custom Aspect Ratio and rotation (both from Core API rotation and from menu video rotation), Integer Scaling is now working properly (correct multiples of internal resolution). Even when Integer Scaling is not activated, the Custom AR width / height are now correctly labeled using (1x), (2x), ... suffixes. You also have to activate Integer Scaling after menu video rotation for it to work.</li>
          <li>OPENGL: For all other Aspect Ratio options, Integer Scaling and rotation (both from Core API rotation and from menu video rotation) are now working properly together (correct multiples of internal resolution). You also have to activate Integer Scaling after menu video rotation for it to work.</li>
          <li>PLAYLISTS: Pressing 'Start' or long touching a playlist will bring you to a Playlist submenu where you can set a default core, setup thumbnail view, delete the playlist, etc.</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Manual scanner, not dependent on database files.</li>
          <li>SCANNER/MANUAL: Add option to scan inside archives.</li>
          <li>SCANNER/MANUAL: Enable automatic naming of arcade content via DAT files. This is compatible with DAT files in either Logiqx XML or MAME List XML format.</li>
          <li>VIDEO: Do not reinit video driver on SET_SYSTEM_AV_INFO unless needed.</li>
          <li>VIDEO: Support DRC even when using a vsync swap interval higher than 1.</li>
          <li>VIDEO LAYOUT: Fixed XML parsing of attributes with spaces, should fix issues with several video layouts.</li>
          <li>VULKAN/ANDROID: Workaround weird WSI return codes in landscape mode -  Android WSI wants you to use preTransform, and if it is not used correctly, Android 10 will return VK_SUBOPTIMAL_KHR, and we would create a new swapchain every frame. This workaround just ignores this error, since it's not really an error. A more "proper" fix is to use prerotate and modify the MVP matrices,
          which might help certain devices with crummy display processors.</li>
          <li>VULKAN/ANDROID: Recreate swapchain on orientation change. ANativeWindow getWidth/Height does not detect any changes when using
          Vulkan, so use the old onContentRectChanged callback to get notified when size changed. Use those values instead when figuring out how large swapchain to create.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.1" date="2019-11-03">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-8-1-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>BUGFIX/MENU: Fix menu rendering with Mali GPUs after changing video dimensions</li>
          <li>CDROM: Adds pregap support to cdfs helper methods</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Provides the new PCEngine hashing algorithm for RetroAchievements</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update French translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Initial thumbnail support</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Cutie / Virtual Boy theme added</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Bugfix - Under certain extreme circumstances, entries with very long sublabel strings could have their text prematurely &#39;clipped&#39; as the entry is scrolled beyond the top of the screen</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Bugfix - Certain setting value strings were unnecessarily truncated (with a ...) when using smooth ticker text</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Sunbeam theme added</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.0" date="2019-10-26">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-8-0-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AI SERVICE: Added in fix for BMP returns to AI service</li>
          <li>BSV: Fix BSV recording/playback</li>
          <li>BUGFIX: Fix crash when setting Thumbnail Directory</li>
          <li>BUGFIX/STABILITY: Set "Automatically Add Content to Playlist" to false by default</li>
          <li>COMMON: Graceful driver switching for Windows and Linux</li>
          <li>COMMON: Cache frame before converting 0RGB1555</li>
          <li>MENU: Menu scaling improvements</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: There are no longer any animation glitches when 'wraparound' scrolling from the last entry in a list to the first, or when performing horizontal swipe navigation gestures on certain settings-type entries</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: List entries underneath the title and navigation bars are no longer highlighted when touching the title/navigation bars</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The current menu list is no longer reloaded when pressing the currently active tab on the navigation bar</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The ticker text spacer has been set to a 'bullet' character (same as Ozone)</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The default colour theme has been set to 'Ozone Dark'</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Three new colour themes have been added</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: A new Menu Transition Animation option has been added under User Interface > Appearance</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The navigation bar is now shown at all times</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Two new context-sensitive buttons have been added to the navigation bar - back button and resume button</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: A new Auto-Rotate Navigation Bar option has been added under User Interface > Appearance</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The playlists tab is now correctly hidden when User Interface > Views > Show Playlist Tabs is disabled</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Material UI now correctly readjusts its layout when screen orientation changes on mobile devices</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Material UI now resizes in real-time when the user manually sets the Menu Scale Factor (this never worked properly with the old DPI override)</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Material UI no longer leaks memory on 'context reset' (fonts were previously never free()'d)</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: A new Android-style 'system bar' has been added. This shows current core name, clock and battery level</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: A new search icon is shown on the title bar when viewing playlists and file browser lists</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The title bar now uses a larger font, and the sublabel font has also been enlarged a little, to more closely align with Material UI standards</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: A number (quite a large number) of layout/spacing issues have been fixed</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: The existing colour theme handling code is not fit for purpose, so the whole lot got ripped out and reimplemented</li>
          <li>OSD: Fix fast forward indicator when not using menu widgets</li>
          <li>VIDEO LAYOUT: Add video layout mame overlay compatibility</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.9" date="2019-10-07">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-7-9-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AI SERVICE: Image mode is now much faster</li>
          <li>BUGFIX: Touch input - When using an overlay to toggle the quick menu on touchscreen devices</li>
          <li>BUGFIX: Networking - RetroArch crashed when pressing left while Relay Server Location entry was selected</li>
          <li>BUGFIX: Networking - fix memory leak that could happen at exit after a network
          operation had run</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Improve handling of line endings when calculating CD hashes for retroachievements</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Add support for Sega CD/Saturn; reduce hash calls to server</li>
          <li>FPGA: Add initial FPGA port for Z-Turn boards - not really release-ready yet, will need community support to continue. Currently employs naive framebuffer approach, not fullspeed</li>
          <li>GL1: GLDirect (D3D9 to OGL1.1 wrapper) support</li>
          <li>GONG: Stability fixes</li>
          <li>LINUX/UDEV: Fix touchscreen/lightgun issues</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: MaterialUI no longer 'forgets' its place when navigating backwards in menus, and navigation in general is 'cleaner'.</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Add initial gesture support</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Improved touch support</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Bugfix - Random' items are no longer automatically highlighted when performing standard up/down 'flick' scrolling through lists</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Bugfix - The display no longer 'jerks' for one frame when navigating backwards through lists</li>
          <li>MENU/MATERIALUI: Bugfix - The Material UI scaling factor is now based upon the device-reported screen DPI value (previously it relied upon a hard-coded magic number, which was never correct)</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Functional mouse/touchscreen support</li>
          <li>MENU/ONSCREEN KEYBOARD: On-screen keyboard entry via mouse/touchscreen has been tidied up - no more double inputs (or unwanted menu interaction in the background)</li>
          <li>MENU/MOUSE: Mouse wheel up/down is now a proper 'up/down', same as using cursor keys or a dpad</li>
          <li>MENU/MOUSE: Mouse wheel tilt left/right has been wired up to normal 'left/right' commands</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add option to toggle between static and scrolling content metadata</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add full gesture support</li>
          <li>MENU: When navigating backwards from a core options drop-down list (i.e. pressing select or cancel), the last menu position is remembered (instead of resetting back to the first core option item each time)</li>
          <li>MENU: Add mouse/touchscreen gesture support</li>
          <li>MENU: Add option to delete playlists (Settings and Playlists: Playlist Management)</li>
          <li>OSD: Memory details should now be available on every platform (get_mem_total and get_mem_free need to be implemented in the frontend driver for it to work)</li>
          <li>OSD: Memory details can now be shown individually without FPS and frame count</li>
          <li>THREADED VIDEO: Fix FPS text in threaded video mode</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.8" date="2019-08-30">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-7-8-v2-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AI: Add AI Service functionality</li>
          <li>AI: Fix 'Japanese' setting</li>
          <li>BPS/UPS: Re-allocation target_data variable for target patch size</li>
          <li>CDROM: Added real CD-ROM functionality for Windows and Linux</li>
          <li>CDROM: Added disc dumping</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Fix Achievements badges</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Add hashing support for PSX (bin/cue, chd, or real CD)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add separate frontend logging</li>
          <li>COMMON: Ability to set FPS update interval (used in the window titlebar/FPS widget)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add 'Reset Frame Time Counter' functionality</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add optional 'on demand' thumbnail downloads</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add new playlist-based thumbnail downloader</li>
          <li>COMMON: Show license per core (if available) inside 'Load Core'</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add option to load content from (and dump) CD-ROM discs</li>
          <li>COMMON: Re-enable '--log-file' command line option</li>
          <li>COMMON: Default playlist core association is now stored as metadata inside each playlist</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix playlist format detection</li>
          <li>COMMON: Favorites playlist size can now be set independently of content history size</li>
          <li>COMMON: Prevent adding new items to favorites when playlist is full (old entries are no longer overwritten)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Prevent loading content with cores that require an incompatible graphics API version from the current one</li>
          <li>COMMON: Saved shader presets are now portable across platforms and use relative paths</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add '--set-shader' command line option which works like an override for automatic shader presets</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add global shader presets</li>
          <li>COMMON: Remove 'video_shader' setting, shaders are not saved automatically anymore</li>
          <li>CORE OPTIONS: When saving core option overrides, only include settings for the current core</li>
          <li>CORE OPTIONS: Add option to save core options per-core</li>
          <li>CPU FILTERS: Add Scanline2x filter</li>
          <li>GL/MALI400: Fix menu issues on Mali 400 series GPUs, should also fix 'RetroArch flickers black on ARM Mali GPUs (Android/ARM Linux)</li>
          <li>GL/GLCORE: Use highest supported OpenGL Core version on Windows and X11</li>
          <li>GL1: Ignore alpha in core video, fixes XRGB8888 rendering in some cores</li>
          <li>GLCORE: Don't hardcode shader cross compilation target version but poll it</li>
          <li>GLCORE: Fix regression - shaders don't work</li>
          <li>GLCORE/SLANG: Added "FrameDirection slang semantic</li>
          <li>HID: Add Retrode support. Should work on Wii/WiiU</li>
          <li>INPUT: Menu toggle hotkey can now be bound to another keyboard key and it will toggle properly</li>
          <li>LIBRETRO: Add new core options interface, allows for localization, sublabels and more</li>
          <li>LIBRETRO: Add new bitmask input codepath, for RETRO_DEVICE_ID_JOYPAD only for now</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Korean translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese Brazilian Translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Turkish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Korean translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Smooth vertical ticker scrolling</li>
          <li>MENU: Add smooth ticker text</li>
          <li>MENU: Ability to hide every settings submenu (User Interface, Views, Settings)</li>
          <li>MENU: Ability to hide nearly every quick menu entry (User Interface, Views, Quick Menu)</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix longstanding menu display issues on Mali400 GPUs (on ARM hardware, SBCs and mobile phones/tablets)</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix Record Streaming Quality, and Record, Recording Threads settings</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix history playlist navigation after running content</li>
          <li>NENU: Menu entry performance optimisations</li>
          <li>MENU: Add option to show 'remove playlist entry' only on history/favourites</li>
          <li>MENU: Overhaul content 'Information' menu display</li>
          <li>MENU: Add new 'Playlist Management' submenu. Allows default core associations to be set (via dropdown list), and all existing associations to be reset</li>
          <li>MENU: Add 'Set Core Association' option to Quick Menu</li>
          <li>MENU: Add option to remain in menu after saving/loading states</li>
          <li>MENU: Pressing the Start button on 'Load Core' will unload the core</li>
          <li>MENU: After a core is running, Load Core will be hidden from view until you select 'Close Content' from the Quick Menu</li>
          <li>MENU/WIDGETS: All widgets are now properly cleaned up, fixing the frozen widgets bug when loading / closing content</li>
          <li>MENU/WIDGETS: Fix crash with tasks</li>
          <li>MENU/WIDGETS: Widgets are now drawn above the overlay with OpenGL and Vulkan</li>
          <li>MENU/WIDGETS: Fine tune progress bar colors</li>
          <li>MENU/WIDGETS: Have the progression widget always resize</li>
          <li>MENU/THUMBNAILS: Ensure that displayed thumbnails are always refreshed correctly after selecting 'Download Thumbnails' from Quick Menu</li>
          <li>MENU/THUMBNAILS: Make PNG image loading/processing non-blocking on non-threaded systems</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add it for PS3</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Fix regression in 1.7.7 - OSX/macOS - was unable to start it</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Fix sublabel spacing</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add toggle to enable/disable playlist name truncation in Ozone</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: (Ozone) Fix display of (semi-)transparent thumbnails</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add menu animation settings</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add optional thumbnail scaling</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Fix display of long sublabels. Text that would exceed the display area now scrolls line-by-line</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB/OZONE: Add optional thumbnail upscaling</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add core option sublabels as tooltips, add buttons to reset one/all core options</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Word-wrap core option tooltips</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Path selector fixes</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Enable playlist display on platforms without database support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Make particle effects framerate independent + add animation speed setting</li>
          <li>MIDI: correct pitch bend in ALSA driver - MIDI standard pitch bend center position is 0x2000 but ALSA's is 0</li>
          <li>MIDI: Fix SysEx handling</li>
          <li>OSD: OSD is now drawn above the overlay with Vulkan</li>
          <li>PATCH: Fix IPS patches</li>
          <li>PLAYLISTS: Fix playlist heap corruption bug</li>
          <li>PLAYLISTS: Add history/favourites to 'Playlist Management' menu</li>
          <li>RECORD: Fix Twitch streaming</li>
          <li>REMOTE RETROPAD: Fix for Remote RetroPad input</li>
          <li>RUNAHEAD/MSVC2010:  Build in runahead support for MSVC2010 and up</li>
          <li>RUNAHEAD/VITA: Build in runahead support for Vita version</li>
          <li>SAVESTATES: Allow auto save states also in cores that support no content as long as some content is loaded</li>
          <li>SCALER: Fix SSE2 path for ARGB/BGRA -&gt; BGR24 - should fix screenshots being taken for XRGB888 (viewport)</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Skip all databases with incompatible file extensions, whether content is inside an archive or not</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Fix hang on empty files inside archives</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Fix shader loading and saving in content-less cores</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Implement video shader delay setting</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Add proper shader compatibility checks</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Enable Cg shaders for D3D9</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Remove 'video_shader' setting, replace it with global presets that make more sense</li>
          <li>SHADERS: #reference directive for shaders. Presets can point to other existing presets if they are unchanged</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Will attempt to cache the shader/preset into memory before loading to avoid costly getline/gets/getc operations</li>
          <li>SHADERS: New --set-shader commandline option</li>
          <li>SHADERS/MENU: Prevent undefined behaviour when failing to load shaders</li>
          <li>SHADERS/MENU: Pressing the Start button on 'Load Shader Preset' will reset all shader passes and apply changes, effectively disabling the shaders</li>
          <li>SHADERS/MENU: New menu options for removing shader presets (global/core/parent/etc)</li>
          <li>THUMBNAILS: Add optional On-Demand Thumbnails</li>
          <li>UDEV: Fix wrong udev devices order</li>
          <li>UDEV/X11: Mouse pointer should work now in X11 environment with no Display</li>
          <li>VULKAN/SLANG: Added "FrameDirection" slang semantic</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Add option to select which GPU to render with</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Validate non-causal filter chain for texture inputs. We only validated for UBO inputs apparently</li>
          <li>WII: Add default video/audio filter directories</li>
          <li>X11: Add improved menu resizing for window resizing</li>
          <li>X11: Add non-evdev keycodes to fix keyboard input on non-Linux systems with X11</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.7" date="2019-05-07">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-7-7-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AUDIO: Avoid deadlocks in certain audio drivers when toggling menu sounds on</li>
          <li>BLISS-BOX: Support PSX Jogcon (requires firmware 3.0)</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Fix crash when reading memory that is out of range</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: New Cheevos implementation enabled by default</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Pop-up badges when an achievement is triggered</li>
          <li>CRT: Dynamic super resolution support</li>
          <li>DISCORD: Fix potential crash when username is empty and discord is disabled</li>
          <li>DISCORD: Ask to join support for Linux</li>
          <li>INPUT/ANDROID: Add "Input Block Timeout" option</li>
          <li>COMMON: For platforms without HAVE_THREADS, don't automatically resume content when saving/loading states</li>
          <li>COMMON: Make playlist sorting optional and consistent</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix sorting of playlists with blank labels</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix content scanner creating false positive playlist entries that also have wrong label and crc32</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add some MMX-optimized pixel conversion routines</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix typo preventing some SSE2-optimized pixel conversions from being used</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add option to track how long content has been running over time</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix buffer overflows in system information</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add option to change screen orientation via the windowing system (Android, Windows, X11)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Show CPU model name in log</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add "Help -> Send Debug Info" option (and F10 hotkey) to send diagnostic info to the RetroArch team for help with problems</li>
          <li>COMMON: Show GPU device name/version in log</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add menu option to write log info to a file</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add subsystem support for playlists. Subsystem info is automatically saved to the history playlist for easy relaunching</li>
          <li>GL: Add new "gl1" OpenGL 1.1 compliant video driver for legacy GPUs and software renderers</li>
          <li>GL: Add a new "glcore" driver with slang support (requires GL 3.2+ or GLES3)</li>
          <li>GL: Draw OSD on top of overlay</li>
          <li>GONG: Add savestate support</li>
          <li>GONG: Add video refresh rate core options</li>
          <li>GONG: Two player support via core option</li>
          <li>GUI: Fix text alignment when using stb_unicode</li>
          <li>GUI: Fix text display issues when using Japanese (and other unicode-dependent language) text with stb_unicode</li>
          <li>GUI: Set language on first startup to the user's preferred OS language (Windows, *nix and Android)</li>
          <li>INPUT: Add (scaled radial) analog deadzone and sensitivity options</li>
          <li>LIBRETRO: Add Turkish language support</li>
          <li>LIBRETRO: Allow non-accelerated video to rotate the display</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Chinese (Simplified) translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Chinese (Traditional) translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Dutch translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update French translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update German translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Russian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Add new Turkish translation</li>
          <li>MIDI: Fix startup crash in midi driver</li>
          <li>MENU: Bugfix - you can no longer get stuck in Online Updater -> Update Core screen when toggling between ingame and menu</li>
          <li>MENU: Selectively hide 'Take Screenshot' for video drivers that don't support taking screenshots</li>
          <li>MENU: Framerate independent menu rendering. MaterialUI/Ozone/XMB/RGUI can now run at higher framerates</li>
          <li>MENU: Thumbnails work in history list</li>
          <li>MENU: Menu widgets</li>
          <li>MENU: Add memory statistics support to more context drivers</li>
          <li>MENU: Enable ozone driver for UWP builds</li>
          <li>MENU: Add optional "looping" menu text ticker with configurable speed</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix core video rendering when using ozone with GL cores that implement the scissor test</li>
          <li>MENU: Add optional playlist sublabels (associated core + play time, where available)</li>
          <li>MENU: Dropdown list settings now apply immediately</li>
          <li>MENU: Add setting to require pressing the "Exit RetroArch" hotkey twice to confirm</li>
          <li>MENU: Now able to run at higher refresh rates than 60Hz</li>
          <li>MENU: Enable "Add to Favorites" without loading a core</li>
          <li>MENU: Allow core name to be hidden on history/favorites playlists</li>
          <li>MENU: Populate crc32 and db_name fields when adding history/favourites playlist entries</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix TTF files not showing in OSD/menu font selection screen</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix audio/video filters not showing in file browser</li>
          <li>MENU/MaterialUI: Add subsystem support</li>
          <li>MENU/MaterialUI: Add currently selected entry in dropdown menus</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add mouse support on entries (no sidebar yet)</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Allow collapsing the sidebar</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add thumbnail support</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Battery notifications</li>
          <li>MENU/OZONE: Add wifi icon for network entries</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add git version and build date to Help->About window</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Fix content loading via the file browser</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add new settings window to control all RetroArch settings</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Improve playlist titles</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add option to hide associated cores in playlists</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add internal upscaling option</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add subsystem support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add menu sublabel support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Re-enable "Load Core" option when content is loaded</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add optional "Collections" entry to main menu</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add "Lock Menu Aspect Ratio" option</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add "full width" layout option</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Ensure menu color theme is applied immediately</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Fix "Lock Menu Aspect Ratio" option when using custom viewports</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add widescreen support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Allow text to be centred when selecting widescreen layouts</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add inline playlist thumbnail support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add optional shadow effects</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Performance optimizations</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add optional extended ASCII support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add optional delay when loading thumbnails</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add on-screen keyboard</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Battery notifications</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Prevent crashes when resizing to a tiny window</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: XMB honors the 'show menu sublabels' setting now - was previously RGUI only</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Fix stall-out causing total disconnection with >2 players</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Different (more intuitive?) default netplay share policy</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Add hotkey option to toggle hosting on/off</li>
          <li>NETWORKING: Encode URLs to allow for spaces in directory names</li>
          <li>SCANNER: New option 'Scan without core match'</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Don't alphabetize shader presets</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix color issues with RGBA8888 swapchains in readback (screenshots)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.6" date="2019-02-03">
      <url>https://www.libretro.com/index.php/retroarch-1-7-6-released/</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Reset when hardcore mode is toggled</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Update the hashing methods to identify NES, SNES and Lynx games (more accurate and accepting headerless ROMs)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add new JSON playlist format</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix playlist corruption when deleting items</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix archive progress display calculation</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix playlist entries appearing with previously used names</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix screenshot filename with no core or content</li>
          <li>COMMON: Allow compiling without menu support</li>
          <li>CORE UPDATER: Allow sideloading cores from the menu</li>
          <li>CPU FILTERS: Add Normal2x filter</li>
          <li>CRT/LINUX: New Linux switching method partially implemented</li>
          <li>CRT/LINUX: Linux restore desktop resolution fixed</li>
          <li>CRT/LINUX: Monitor index switching and auto enumerate for output detection in Linux (still working on the windows method)</li>
          <li>CRT/RASPBERRY PI: Initial support</li>
          <li>DATE: Add Date / Time style options</li>
          <li>DEBUGGING: Add an integrated crash handler for debug builds</li>
          <li>DISCORD: Register the application name properly</li>
          <li>DISK CONTROL: Remember the last used folder / current active folder to make disk-swapping faster</li>
          <li>INPUT: Add new menu toggle (hold start button for 2 seconds)</li>
          <li>INPUT: Fix arrow keys being incorrectly bound as numpad keys</li>
          <li>INPUT/SDL: Flush the joypad events. Decreases cpu usage over time with the SDL joypad driver</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Add Greek translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update German translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Simplified Chinese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>MENU: New "ozone" menu driver</li>
          <li>MENU: Only show CRT SwitchRes if video display server is implemented (Windows/Linux for now)</li>
          <li>MENU: User Interface -> Appearance -> 'Menu Font Green/Blue Color' settings now work properly</li>
          <li>MENU: Add option to enable in-menu sound effects</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Allow building with MSVC2017</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add detailed file browser table</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: New grid view implementation that is faster and loads thumbnails on-demand</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Thumbnail drag and drop support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Overhaul custom theme interface + add wallpaper support</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Thumbnail support and thumbnail downscaling</li>
          <li>MENU: Hide password values</li>
          <li>MENU/SOUNDS: Implement in-menu sound effects (not enabled by default for now, still experimental)</li>
          <li>MIDI: Add a Linux ALSA driver for MIDI</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Force fast-save-states when netplay is enabled</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Allow quick joining subsystem lobbies</li>
          <li>RECORDING: Implement recording options in the menu complete with quality profiles, streaming, and proper file naming</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Fix GDI disc scanning</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Fix auto shader preset loading on D3D10, D3D11, D3D12</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: Allow more than 10 subsystems</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: Cores that use subsystem for complex scenarios can now load content without starting a regular content first</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: Remember the last used folder to make loading subsystem type content faster</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix RGUI crashing at startup</li>
          <li>VULKAN/RGUI: Enable 'Menu Linear Filter' option</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix secondary screens in overlays not working</li>
          <li>WAYLAND: Implement idle-inhibit support (needed for screensaver suspend)</li>
          <li>WAYLAND: Fix fullscreen toggle</li>
          <li>VFS: Update to version 3</li>
          <li>XBONE: Initial Xbox One port</li>
          <li>XMB/OZONE: Add more icons</li>
          <li>Easter egg</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.5" date="2018-10-2">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>CAMERA: Fix Video4Linux2 driver that broke years ago</li>
          <li>CONFIG: Add 'Reset To Defaults' setting in Configurations. Thi will reset your config file to defaults</li>
          <li>CHEATS: Add support for Rumble when increase or decrease by the rumble value</li>
          <li>CHEATS: Add cheat variables to allow for updating large portions of memory</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Prevent loading states before achievements are fully loaded</li>
          <li>COMMON: Support for "OEM-102" key (usually '' on Euro keyboards)</li>
          <li>DISCORD: Add 'Ask To Join' Feature</li>
          <li>INPUT: Add new menu toggle combos 'L3 + R' and 'L + R' (useful for Switch)</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese / Brazilian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>MENU: Add dropdown lists for many settings</li>
          <li>MENU: Fix crash that could happen when changing core's options on Android</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add option to rename playlists</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add option to filter extensions inside archives when adding to a playlist</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Rename playlist entries with 2 single clicks</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Fix shader parameter checkboxes not working</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Save lobby details received back from server after first announcement</li>
          <li>OPENGL/GLX: Implement Adaptive VSync - GLX_EXT_swap_control_tear</li>
          <li>OPENGL/WGL: Implement Adaptive VSync - WGL_EXT_swap_control_tear</li>
          <li>RUNAHEAD: Fix performance degradation that could happen over time (after approx. 30 mins). Fixed input IDs outside of range 0-35 causing slow performance in runahead</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix race condition in threaded mailbox emulation</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Maintenance fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.4" date="2018-08-30">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Fix crash when scrolling Achievement List while Unofficial Achievements enabled (#6732)</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Added hitcounts support for PauseIf/ResetIf (#6817)</li>
          <li>COMMON: Automatically hide "Configuration Override options" in Quick Menu</li>
          <li>COMMON: Small Bugfix to not trigger savestate code when pressing Reset</li>
          <li>COMMON: Added libsixel video driver</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese / Brazilian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Russian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>MIDI: Add MIDI support to the libretro API. Dosbox is the first proof of concept core implementing libretro MIDI</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Qt QSlider styling for Dark Theme</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Remove button ghostly inside highlighting</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Initial grid view</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Drag and drop to add new playlist items, add option to add/edit/delete playlists</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add menu option to update RetroArch (Windows only for now)</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add menu option to manage shaders</li>
          <li>MENU/QT/WIMP: Add menu option to manage core options</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add new icons for the settings</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add an option to show the desktop ui</li>
          <li>NETWORK: Enable SSL/TLS support by default for desktop platforms</li>
          <li>REMAPS: Fix the way offsets are calculated for keyboard remapping</li>
          <li>RUNAHEAD: Fix full-screen mode change breaking Secondary Core's environment variables</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix two validation errors</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Try to avoid creating swapchains redundantly. Should fix black screen and having to alt tab out of window again to get display working on Nvidia GPUs (Windows)</li>
          <li>X11: Fix Game Focus Toggle</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.3" date="2018-05-03">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AUDIO: Audio mixer supports FLAC/MP3 file types now</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fixed bug 'crashing in cores that don't range check retro_set_controller_type'</li>
          <li>COMMON: (QuickMenu) Added Configuration Override submenu</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese translation</li>
          <li>MENU: Audio mixer now works in the menu without any cores loaded. You have to enable the setting 'Enable menu audio' for this to work</li>
          <li>REMAPPING/OVERLAYS: Fix regression - overlays could no longer be remapped</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Add Wii Backup File WBFS support</li>
          <li>X11: CRT SwitchRes support for X11/Linux</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.2" date="2018-04-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>CRT: Added CRT SwitchRes</li>
          <li>COMMON: Hide the 'Core delete' option if the 'Core updater' is also hidden</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add way to reset core association for playlist entry</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix invalid long command line options causing infinite loop on Windows</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add OSD statistics for video/audio/core</li>
          <li>COMMON: Added runahead system; allows you to drive down latency even further</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Support Atari 2600, Virtual Boy, and Arcade (only Neo Geo, CPS-1, CPS-2 and CPS-3 and only with fbalpha core)</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Add option to automatically take a screenshot when an achievement is triggered</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Fixed incompatibilities with Neo Geo Pocket achievement sets</li>
          <li>LIBRETRO: Addition - Functions to enable and disable audio and video, and an environment function to query status of audio and video enables</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>MENU: Add Rewind/Latency/Overlay settings to Quick Menu, add options to show/hide them (User Interface -> Views -> Quick Menu)</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Only show Menu Linear Filter for RGUI and only show it for video drivers that implement it (D3D8/9/10/11/12/GL)</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: Add User Interface -> Appearance options</li>
          <li>MENU/RGUI: D3D8/D3D9: Hookup Menu Linear Filter</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Disable XMB shadow icons by default for PowerPC and ARM for performance reasons</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Left/right thumbnails are now automatically scaled according to layout</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add Left Thumbnails (additional to the right)</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Fixed left/right tab regression</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Fix scaling of tall images that were cut on bottom previously</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Menu scale factor setting now changes texts length, image scaling and margins</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Mouse cursor scales correctly now</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add toggle to show/hide Playlist tabs</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Add menu layout - can switch between Desktop, Handheld and Auto</li>
          <li>MENU/XMB: Don't load menu pipeline shaders unless XMB is selected (D3D10/D3D11/D3D12/GL/Vulkan)</li>
          <li>MENU/VIDEO: Only show black frame insertion for the video drivers/context drivers that support it (so far this includes - D3D8/D3D9, OpenGL, Vulkan)</li>
          <li>MENU/VIDEO: Only show max swapchain images if supported by video driver and/or context driver (so far this includes - DRM EGL context driver, VideoCore EGL context driver, Vulkan)</li>
          <li>MENU/MaterialUI: Automatic DPI Scaling should be much improved now, now scales as expected at 1440p and 4K resolutions</li>
          <li>MENU/MaterialUI: Fix wrong calculation of an entry height causing long playlists to end up outside of screen range. This also could cause crashes on low DPI screens</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Should be able to scan dual-layer Wii disc images now, filestream code now supports files larger than 4GB</li>
          <li>SHADERS/SLANG: Slang shaders should work again on Android version and MSVC versions (basically all the Griffin-based versions)</li>
          <li>SHADERS: If GL context is GLES2/3/Core context, Cg shaders are unavailable. Applies to shader list too</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Hide cg/glsl shaders from being able to be selected if D3D8/9/10/11/Vulkan video drivers are selected</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Hide slang shaders from being able to be selected if D3D8/9/OpenGL video drivers are selected</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Prevent crashes from occurring if we have the GL video driver in use and we try to skip to a slang shader through next/previous hotkeys</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Fix shader parameter increase / decrease functions</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: handle savestates properly (cart1 + cart2.state0)</li>
          <li>VULKAN/X11: Fix X11 Vulkan bug from Wayland driver</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix multi-line text spacing in menus with Vulkan driver</li>
          <li>X11: Allow compositor disabling on X11 fullscreen through _NET_WM_BYPASS_COMPOSITOR</li>
          <li>X11: Prioritize _NET_WM_STATE_FULLSCREEN in true fullscreen mode</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.1" date="2018-02-19">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>AUDIO: Added 'Audio Resampler Quality' setting to Audio Settings</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Fix unofficial achievements not being loaded</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Show savestate menu entries when no achievements are found even if hardcore mode is enabled</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Support Neo Geo Pocket</li>
          <li>COMMON: Bugfix for issue related to 'Windows mouse pointer visible when running MESS or MAME cores'</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix bug 'Last item in a Playlist is ignored'</li>
          <li>COMMON: New LED API. Driver implemented for Raspberry Pi, proof of concept implemented for core MAME 2003</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add quick menu option to watch shader files for changes and recompile them automatically (Linux only for now)</li>
          <li>D3D8: Direct3D 8 can now work on systems that have Direct3D 8 installed</li>
          <li>INPUT: show friendly names when available under input binds and system information</li>
          <li>INPUT: show the config name when available under system information</li>
          <li>GUI: Allow changing menu font color</li>
          <li>GUI: Menu visibility options for RGUI and MaterialUI</li>
          <li>GUI/MaterialUI: Works now with D3D8, D3D9 Cg, D3D11 and D3D12 drivers</li>
          <li>GUI/XMB: Add Monochrome Inverted icon theme</li>
          <li>GUI/XMB: Allow changing menu scale to 200%</li>
          <li>GUI/XMB: Works now with D3D8, D3D9 Cg, D3D11 and D3D12 drivers. Menu shader effects currently don't work on D3D8/D3D9 Cg</li>
          <li>KEYMAPPER: prevent a condition that caused input_menu_toggle to stop working when a RETRO_DEVICE_KEYBOARD type device is enabled</li>
          <li>GL: ignore hard gpu sync when fast-forwarding</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese-Brazilian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Spanish translation</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Add menu option to select different MITM (relay) server locations</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Allow saving of shader presets based on the parent directory</li>
          <li>SHADERS: Don't save the path to the current preset to the main config</li>
          <li>SHADERS: SPIRV-Cross/slang shader support for D3D11</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: Subsystem saves now respect the save directory</li>
          <li>SUBSYSTEM: You can now load subsystem games from the menu</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Fix swapchain recreation bug on Nvidia GPUs with Windows 10 (resolved in Windows Nvidia driver version 390.77)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="2017-12-25">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Add badges for achievements, shows thumbnail images of achievements</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Leaderboard support</li>
          <li>CHEEVOS: Only disable savestates on hardcore mode if achievements are not available</li>
          <li>COMMANDLINE: Fix fullscreen toggle switch</li>
          <li>COMMON: Add 'Automatically Load Content To Playlist' feature, enabled by default</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix slowmotion ratio always being reset back to 1</li>
          <li>COMMON: Optimized NBIO implementations now for Apple, Windows, and Linux. Uses mmap for Linux/Windows/BSD if/when available. File I/O should now be much faster for loading images inside the menu</li>
          <li>COMMON: Native Blissbox support now for latest firmware as of writing (2.0). Implementation through libusb and/or native Windows HID</li>
          <li>COMMON: New lightgun API</li>
          <li>COMMON: New VFS (Virtual File System) API</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fixed some playlist bugs</li>
          <li>COMMON: New snow shader</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix Quick Menu title, no longer shows 'Select File'</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix loading cores that require no content one after another</li>
          <li>COMMON: Map Delete key to Y button for non-unified menu keyboard controls</li>
          <li>COMMON: Fix for relative paths being normalised and generating a duplicate history entry</li>
          <li>INPUT: Map clear button to DEL key</li>
          <li>LINUX/X11: Add RetroArch logo to window title bar</li>
          <li>LINUX/X11: Input driver now supports new lightgun code</li>
          <li>LINUX/X11: Support window transparency (requires a compositing window manager)</li>
          <li>LOBBIES: Fix for crash on join netplay rooms via touch / glui</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Italian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Japanese translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Portuguese-Brazilian translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Polish translation</li>
          <li>LOCALIZATION: Update Russian translation</li>
          <li>MENU: Snowflake menu shader effect</li>
          <li>SCANNER: Fix crash from Windows-incompatible format string</li>
          <li>VULKAN: Various stability fixes for WSI</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.9" date="2017-11-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>COMMON: Small memory leak</li>
          <li>NETPLAY: Fix network command only working once</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
